## JAVA DEVELOPER

**Profile** 

Information Technology professional with over 25 years experience in software design, development, analysis, testing, implementation, and maintenance of various software products. I am a highly skilled, motivated, analytical and dependable professional who is seeking new challenges to build upon previous work experience and educational background. I amcurrently working as a Java developer / application support for the VNAS application (Verizon Numbering AutomationSystem).

Core Qualifications

Java, JavaScript, JSP, Servlets, Stripes, Hibenate, Agile Scrum, Subversion, Eclispe, C/C++, HTML/XML, Oracle, PL/SQL, SQL, TOAD, sh/ksh, vi, RPG III, and AS/400 Control Language

Professional Experience

Java Developer

November 2009 Amerisourcebergen Corporation - Corporate - Guaynabo, PR

- Created various maintenance screens for VNAS (Verizon Numbering Automation System).
- Created new screen to aid in removing unnecessary files from Nortel switches after major feature upgrades which was well received with our users.
- Was one of the primary developers on the STP Image Collection project where I worked on establishing connectivity with the 18 production SS7 STP's and Lab STP.
- Worked through various issues in connecting and retrieving data from the Tekelec STP's.
- Created scripts and java code to successfully connect to the STP's anddump GTT table data for all three translation types (T3, T12, and T14).
- Created a parsing utility to parse the GTT tabledata retrieved as part of our image collection process and then uploaded into our tables.
- Made updates to imagecollection process to pull new switch forms for Lucent and Nortel switches which involved writing java code to parse thedata into text files which was later used to upload into the VNAS database.
- Modified the Lucent ARG switch form to storethe switch data into 3 separate tables due to Oracles table limitation of 999 columns.
- Fixed various code defects in the VNAS application.
- Application Support, Managed switch connectivity and image collection issues for Nortel, Lucent, Compaq HLR, Ubicell, and SS7 STP's.
- Monitored VNAS application daily connectivity test and automatic password updates and resolveissues that occurred.
- Help setup auth keys on lucent and lucent SMSC switches.
- Update VNAS application with new IORfiles when maintenance updates had been performed on Verizon Compaq HLR switches.
- Investigate switch batch updateissues for lucent, Nortel, Ubicell, and HLR switches.
- Worked with network teams in supporting switch migration and updates to Verizon Switches.
- Maintained updates to image collection switch form/ table layouts to insure switch formswere kept in sync with Nortel and Lucent switches.
- On occasion data would have to be manually pulled for Nortel switchesand scripts manually executed to load data into the VNAS
  application.
- Investigated UBICELL batch update issues whichsometimes involved making code modifications to resolve issues.
- STP Project help supported project when manualimage collection was needed, trouble shoot image collection issues, maintain STP passwords, and trouble shoot STP connectivity issues.
- Investigate/debug STP batch daemon code to resolve resource issues.
- Documentation, Maintain group Wiki site with information in order to help share knowledge and help other's in resolving issues.
- Some of the updates included a Common Support Issues / Resolutions page, General issues with VNAS connectivity test with Verizon
  switches, Lucent image pull process overview, Lucent FetchImage Process, addedContact Links and Information page to centralize contact
  information, instructions on manually connecting to an STP which included detailed instructions including print screens containing added text
  for clarity and understanding.
- Created general documentation which included documenting an overview of Nortel connectivity to help fellow employees, VCRSsupport
  overview Created overview documentation on support activities and discussed with fellow workers, DisasterRecovery DRILL which gave
  support personnel from other groups an overview of the Disaster Recovery process.
- Disaster Recovery, I was the lead / point of contact for my departments disaster recovery exercise.
- Each year Verizonperforms a disaster recovery exercise simulating a disaster where applications would need to fail over to their disaster recovery server.
- This exercise is monitored and each application is tracked against its desired goals.
- This exercise involved bringing down our Dataguard link which keeps our production database in sync with our disaster recovery database.
- Configurations are made to property / config files to point to the DR database and the application is broughtup.
- Testing is performed to insure we are able to connect, retrieve and update data on the DR database.
- After testing hasbeen completed and it is verified that there are no database issues, we then contact our third party vendors (
   Syniverse, IConnectiv (aka Telecordia), eTNI) and test receiving/transmission of files between Verizon and our external vendors. Outside of the annual DR exercise test, I attended daily/weekly meetings held prior to and during execution of our disaster recovery test.
- After the test, I provide the necessary documentation verifying our applications successful execution.
- I also maintained our application DR Documents providing detailed information with the intent to helpfollowing years execution runs smoother.
- In the documentation, I include information needed to configuration files, highlevel overview of the exercise and detailed information on the tasks required to accomplish our application testing objectives.
- Prior to the disaster recovery test, I communicated with our third party vendors insuring they were prepared tohelp support us in our disaster recovery execution.

- WBI Environment Owner / Portal Environment Owner, which comprised of updating/maintaining environmentspecific files for code
  deployment/retrofits, bouncing components/instances when needed, communication / coordination of downtime among active projects,
  retrofit analysis and deployments, coordination of code deployments, communication to development regarding retrofit overlaps among
  active projects, and participated in SWAT calls for trouble shootingenvironment issues.\* Vitria System Test Environment Owner, updated /
  maintained environment specific files, deployed retrofits to insureenvironment code base was kept up to date, participated in swat calls for
  trouble shooting of environment issues, bounced instances/components when needed.
- Also provided detailed documentation to the new Vitria Development EnvironmentOwner upon my transitioning from development
  environment to the system test environment.\* Routinely monitored and analyzed system test retrofits, insuring the system test environments
  were kept up to date withthe latest code base, which also reduced the number of openretrofit tickets appearing on weekly retrofit reports.
- Vitria Development Environment OwnerApril 2003 to January 2005\* Implemented Development Environment website along with upgrades
  / enhancements This website provided a singlepoint of reference, by developers, for many of their commonly asked questions such as
  Vitria instance port numbers, gateway URL's, instance id's / passwords, Environment standards, Current Development projects and their
  allocated Vitria instance along with the components being modified.
- Much of this work was done after hours on my own personaltime.\* Allocated Development Environment Requests for Vitria and managed project conflicts within the developmentenvironment.
- Development / Quality Assurance and SupportNovember 1994 to March 2003Development Experience Developed and tested various Vitria enhancements, written in Java and C+++.\* Code the CSA print enhancement for eWAVE 8.3.
- This enhancement provided the creation of the Customer ServiceAgreement into a PDF format.
- The business was quite pleased with this enhancement as it provided the customer with aprinter friendly copy of the customer service agreement.\* Developed, tested and maintained various code enhancements to the TSDA project, which was written in C++ to interface to VII
- Developed, tested and maintained various code enhancements for the India Client Development project.
- This projectwas to migrate the Virtuoso II product from a Sybase to Oracle platform\* Migrated Note functionality from ACI Mobile Virtuoso 1 product to the Virtuoso/PCN code base.
- Due to the urgencyand need to impress a potential client, this required 60+ hour work weeks during the 3 months to complete.
- In the process of the code migration, 30+ existing code errors were found in the ACI code base which had to be fixed alongwith the migration of the code.\* Coded, unit tested, system tested, and regression tested enhancements to Virtuoso/PCN Billing System which ran on the AS/400.\* Wrote functional, technical design documents and unit, system, and regression test plans for software enhancements for various projects.
- Quality Assurance and Support \* Accepted a temporary assignment with QA group to help fill a vacancy.\* Automated the manual process, of handling compile only modules during code release builds, which reduced the process from several days down to a few minutes.
- This included creating a user interface menu which was added to the existing source control system.
- Also created various QA tools to help with routine tasks such as creating newdevelopment environments, maintaining library lists, etc.
- Development, Code Integration, and Quality AssuranceJune.

## January 1989 to October 1994 IBM Corporation - City

- Maintained Code Integration Process, for the IMB Atlanta Multimedia Development Lab, using the PVCS code controlsystem
- Development Experience Maintained the Sequence Generator for ProductManager, an IBM object-oriented engineering software product which ran on the main frame.
- Programmed and maintained the General Ledger application for Construction Management Accounting System II, anIBM construction
  industry software product, which ran on the AS/400 platform\* Rewrote the General Ledger Logic Manual, making it technically correct
  and up to date with the current CMAS IIproduct.\* Prototyped the implementation of journaling for CMAS II focusing on needed code
  changes, problems in existing code, and implementation problems.
- Test and Assurance Experience Developed and executed unit, function, and regression test cases for ProductManager which contributed to the overall quality of the product.
- Led team efforts to test design changes for ProductManager which resulted in a decreased development cycle time.\* Extensively tested the journaling implementation which revealed undetected code problems in the CMAS II product.
- Outside Interests/Activities I enjoy woodturning, woodworking, and welding.
- I took a welding class at night Summer 2006 at Lanier TechnicalCollege.
- It's amazing what you can make or fix by heating a little metal.
- I am currently President of the Atlanta Woodturner's Guild.
- I enjoy sharing my woodturning knowledge with others and often write articles for my club's newsletter as a way to share that knowledge.

## Education

BBA: MIS, 1989 University of Georgia - City, State MIS

Certifications

Advance C Language- Southern College of Technology - Fall 1994C Language Southern College of Technology - Fall 1993 Certifications ASTQB Certification - 2011

Skills

Accounting System II, Agile, AS/400, Automation, Billing System, C, C Language, C++, Compaq, config, Construction Management, Client, customer service, database, Disaster Recovery, disaster recovery, Documentation, XML, forms, frame, functional, gateway, General Ledger, HTML, IBM, Image, Java, JSP, JavaScript, ksh, Logic, meetings, migration, Multimedia Development, network, Nortel, object-oriented, Oracle,

PL/SQL, page, PDF, personnel, PVCS, Quality, QA, Quality Assurance, receiving, RPG III, Scrum, Servlets, scripts, SMSC, SQL, SS7, Switches, switch, Sybase, tables, TOAD, translation, transmission, trouble shooting, upgrades, user interface, vi, website, welding, written, articles